Finding Aid for the Ernst Toch Papers PASC-M.0001
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Articles, Essays, Speeches, Lectures, Series 6.
  - About Toch, Subseries 1.
    - Sargeant, Winthrop. "Ernst Toch Views Modern Music as Art of Tone-Color." Musical America, Mar. 1932. (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - "Ernst Toch - Leben und Werk - Kitiken Diskographie." Phillips Klassik Informationen, July 1971. (Box 105, Folder 18)
    - J.S. Trotter about Toch (notes), 1953 (Box 105, Folder 19)
    - Articles from Encyclopedias (Box 105, Folder 20)
      nine articles
    - "Komponisten der Gegenwart." Deutscher Komponisten-Verband. Berlin: 1987. (Box 105, Folder 21)
      Toch entry on page 906.
    - Baker's Biographical Dictionary of Musicians. Fifth ed. New York: G. Schirmer, 1958. (Box 105, Folder 22)
      Toch entry on page 1651.
    - "Classified Chronological Catalog of works by the United States Composer Ernst Toch." Washington D.C.: Union Panamericana, Jan 1962. (Box 105, Folder 23)
  - By Toch, Subseries 2.
    By Toch
    - "Ubergangscharakter der Gegenwarts Musik, n.d.; 3 pages. Typescript (cc). (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - "Tiere", n.d.; 3 pages. Typescript. (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - "Die dreiziffrige zahl", n.d.; 3 pages. Typescript (cc). (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - "So Hingedachtes", n.d.; 1 page. Typescript (cc). With English translation. (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - "Die musikalischen ausdrucksformen im wandel der zeiten", Mannheim, 1920s; 11 pages. Typescript (cc). (incomplete) (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - "Kontrapunkt", 1920s-30s; Publisher's proof with musical examples & Clipping (abridged). (Box 106, Folder 6)
      Mannheimer General-Anzeiger (Aus Zeit und Leben).
    - "Ich habe erfahren: der einfall ist alles..", 1920s; 1 page. Typescript (xerox). (Box 106, Folder 7)
      The Chesterian.
    - "Theremin und komponist", Dec. 6, 1924; Clipping. (Box 106, Folder 8)
      Mannheim: Neue Badische Landeszeitung.
    - "Musik fuer mechanische musikinstrumente", July 21, 1926; Clipping. (Box 106, Folder 9)
      Frankfurter Zeitung
    - "Beethoven in der gegenwart", March 25, 1927; Clipping & typescript (xerox). Includes comments by other composers. (Box 106, Folder 10)
      Neue Leipziger Zeitung
    - "Klavier als instrumentalkoerper", Anbruch, Oct.-Nov. 1927; Clipping. (Box 106, Folder 11)
      Das Klavierbuch, Universal-Edition, page 371.
    - "Schauspielmusik ", 1928/29 (Box 106, Folder 12)
      Stadt Theater Luebeck, page 1.
    - "Glueckwunsch und erinnerung", Mannheim, June 30, 1929; Clipping. [Includes comments by others] (Box 106, Folder 13)
      Neue Badische Landeszeitung.
    - "Von neuer musikform", October 31, 1929; Clipping. (Box 106, Folder 14)
      from "Neue wege der musik." Berliner Tageblatt.
    - "Moderne komponisten ueber die gegenwarsmusik", May 26, 1929; Clipping. [Includes comments of other composers] (Box 106, Folder 15)
      Vienna: Der Tag.
    - "Revue der musikinstrumente, VII, mechanische musikinstruments", October 28, 1930; Clipping. (Box 106, Folder 16)
      Frankfurter Zeitung.
    - "Ueber meine kantate 'Das Wasser' und meine grammophonmusik.", May-June, 1930 (Box 106, Folder 17)
      Melos, v.9, pp. 221-222.
    - "Kompositionsaufzeichnung auf maschinellen Wege", Jan. 5, 1932; Clipping. (Box 106, Folder 18)
      Deutsche Tonkuenstler-Zeitung
    - "Arnold Schoenberg", May 5, 1932; Clipping. (Box 106, Folder 19)
    - "Film-musik", December 18, 1935; 6 pages with cover letter. Typescript (cc). (Box 106, Folder 20)
      [Original German version of "Sound-film & Music Theater," _Modern Music_, January-February 1936]
    - "Einige Gedanken Nebenbei", n.d. (Box 106, Folder 21)
      Sketch
    - "Glaubensbekenntniss eines komponisten", March- April 1945; Clipping. (Box 106, Folder 22)
      Santiago de Chile: Deutsche Blatter, pp. 13-15.
    - Geleitwort fuer um 1948 gegrundete radio organization 'Music of to-day', 2 pages typescript. (Box 106, Folder 23)
      with English translation.
    - "Die Symphony der Erschuetterung.", typescript (Box 106, Folder 24)
    - "Wahrscheinlich Wien" [Radio Ansprache], January 28, 1952; 4 pages; corrected copy, 4 pages. (Box 106, Folder 25)
    - "Was ist gute musik?", January 1955 (Box 106, Folder 26)
      Oesterreichische Musikzeitschrift, pp. 10-15.
    - Autobiographisches aus einem interview mit Frl. Bach vom Bremer Sender, 1958; 2 pages. Typescript. (Box 106, Folder 27)
      [from book published in 1958]
    - Berliner Ansprache zum 75 Geburtstag (Box 106, Folder 28)
    - Skizze zu einer radioansprache, 1962; 4 pages. Typescript. (Box 106, Folder 29)
      Zuerich Radio
    - Eine andere teilweise identische teilweise veraenderte ansprache, 1964; 2 pages. Typescript. (Box 106, Folder 30)
    - "Die Germanen sind bland." (lecture), 2 p. typescript (Box 106, Folder 31)
    - Essay on astrology (Box 106, Folder 32)
      5 pages, typescript
    - "Arnold Schoenberg", May 5, 1932; 2 originals (Box 106, Folder 33)
    - Essay on music, Wagner & patriotism (Box 106, Folder 34)
      6 pages, typescript.
    - "Lieber Symphoniker", Jan. 1952 (Box 106, Folder 35)
      from Wiener Symphoniker program.
    - "Moderne Komponisten ueber die Gegenwartsmusik", May 1929 (Box 106, Folder 36)
      Der Tag.
    - "Melodielehre" (Box 106, Folder 37)
    - Sketch for a radio adress - Zuerich Radio (Box 106, Folder 38)
      in German.
    - "Eidesstattliche Versicherung" (Box 106, Folder 39)
    - "About the teaching of music theory, an address", n.d.; Typescript, 3 pages. (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Letter to Scherchen re: "The Situation of the composer in the USA." (Box 107, Folder 2)
      German and English.
    - Introduction to a chamber music concert, 1932; 3 pages, Typescript (cc). (Box 107, Folder 3)
      (during his American tour for Pro Musica.)
    - "Sound-film and music theatre", Jan-Feb 1936 (Box 107, Folder 4)
      Modern Music, v.13 no.2, pp.15-18.
    - Film music, an address, early 1940s; 3 pages, Typescript (cc) (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - [Blueprint for a demonstration method ..] Typescript (cc). [early 1940s] (Box 107, Folder 6)
      .. in the teaching of instrumentation. 2 pages.
    - "The situation of the composer in U.S.A. - 2nd part." Ars Viva, News Bulletin no.3, March 1940, pp.2-3. (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - "The credo of a composer", 1945; Typescript (cc). 7 pages. (Box 107, Folder 8)
      [translated from German, "Glaubensbekenntniss..", Deutsche Blaetter, 1945.]
    - Introduction and outline to a course in instrumentation (Box 107, Folder 9)
      Annotated draft, 2 pages typescript, c.c., and revised version, 2 pages typescript, c.c.
    - Intro and outline to a course in instrumentation., Typescript (cc), 2 pages. (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - "Finale" (Box 107, Folder 10)
      Related to Albert Goldberg article.
    - Norton, Mildred. "Letters." (Box 107, Folder 11)
      [Toch's remarks on former Nazi, Walter Gieseking, concertizing in the U.S., in response to Mildred Norton's article of January 11, 1954 in Los Angeles newspaper.]
    - Address to the National Institute of Arts and Letters., 1957 (Box 107, Folder 12)
    - anecdote (Box 107, Folder 13)
    - Just what is good music?, 1954.; Mimeo, with corrections. (Box 107, Folder 14)
      11 pages. [Address presented at the University of Minnesota, November 9, 1954.] Preliminary draft, with corrections, typescript, 2 pages. "What is good music?" Musical Courrier, v. 152, no. 6, April 1955, pp. 8-10. [reprinted from above]
    - Tribute to Willi Strecker., Jan 1963 (Box 107, Folder 15)
      Melos Zeitschrift fuer Neue Musik, pg. 14.
    - Lecture: "Having heard Dr. Russel's lecture..", 3 pgs. typescript (Box 107, Folder 16)
    - unknown draft, 10 pgs. pencil (Box 107, Folder 17)
    - "Paper written for the group of Dr. Roman", drafts: typescript and photocopy (Box 107, Folder 18)
    - Acceptance speech for the Order of Merit of the German government., 1957 (Box 107, Folder 19)
    - A Response by Ernst Toch on the occasion of his 75th Birthday Celebration. (Box 107, Folder 20)
      Sponsored by the School of Music, University of Southern California.
    - Lecture: "When the persecuted Hugenots fled.." (Box 107, Folder 21)
    - Notes for a lecture? (Box 107, Folder 22)
    - Lecture: "What has made the man.." (Box 107, Folder 23)
    - Toch, Ernst Some thoughts out of season Performing Arts Special Collections Assoc. Notes, v.22 no.3, March 1966 (Box 107, Folder 24)
      5 pages, original and xerox copy. xerox of draft written 1960 or 1961.
    - Lecture: "The necessary changes.." (Box 107, Folder 25)
    - Lecture: "The discussion on the reeducation of the Germans.." (Box 107, Folder 26)
    - Proposed correction of Bach C-Sharp fugue, Typescript, 3 pages (Box 107, Folder 27)
    - Theme and variations (or: Who stole it from whom?), Typescript, 9 pages, 2 copies. (Box 107, Folder 28)
    - Lecture: "Some viewpoints of the composer", 1957; 6 pages, typescript (Box 107, Folder 29)
      Given during the third "Composer's Workshop" of the Westside Jewish Community Center and the Jewish Music Council of Los Angeles.
    - Lecture: "Finally one word about the attitude of the Jews.." (Box 107, Folder 30)
    - Excerpts from speech on Zuerich Radio, 1964 (Box 107, Folder 31)
    - Lecture: "Then there is the Jewish conception of God.." (Box 107, Folder 32)
    - Radio speech - RIAS, 1963 (Box 107, Folder 33)
    - Essay on new tones; Symphony of the Clouds. (Box 107, Folder 34)
    - Toch, Ernst Comments on his background & music (Box 107, Folder 35)
      2 pages, typescript
    - Clipping on a lecture by Bertrand Russell about Germany (Box 107, Folder 36)
      and a typed commentary/correction by Toch
    - "Nazism as a political power has been defeated.." (Box 107, Folder 37)
    - fragment of lecture draft (Box 107, Folder 38)
    - "An unsere Mitgleider", Mannheim, Juli 1925 (Box 107, Folder 39)
      from Gesellschaft fuer neue Musik
  - About the Music, Subseries 3.
    About the Music
    - Program notes and other essays regarding individual pieces. (Box 108, Folder 1-18)
- Music Manuscripts, Series 7.
  Boxes 109-123. Autograph manuscripts and copies of compositions by Ernst Toch.
  - Variations on a Theme by John Scott Trotter, Copyist's holograph parts 23 parts; 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Thema mit Variationen ueber "Muss i denn zum Stüadle hinaus" (Schwäbisches Volkslied), Ozalid holograph transparencies 15 p.; 11 x 14 in. (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Three pieces for Doctor's Orchestra, Op. 82: Epilogue, Intermezzo, Short Story, Manuscript transparencies (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Punch and Judy, Ozalid holograph transparencies 5 p.; 11 x 14 in. (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Leprechauns, Sketch, holograph 4 p.; 11 x 14 in. (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Dance of the Marionettes, Copyist's holograph parts, 18 parts; 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Epilogue, Ozalid holograph transparencies 12 p.; 11 x 14 in. (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Symphonietta for wind instruments and percussion, Op. 97, Ozalid reproduction of holograph score 20 p.; 11 x 14 in. (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Raisins & Almonds, Jewish lullaby., Holograph score (ink) 1 p.; 9 1/2 x 8 1/2 in. (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - Two Folk Songs, no. 1: "Al Hasela", Holograph score (ink) 1 l.; 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - The Last Tale, op. 88, Incomplete sketches, holograph (pencil) 4 p.; 10 3/4 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Chansons sans paroles, Copyist's score (ink) 3 folded l; 9 1/2 x 12 in. 2 copies each. (Box 109, Folder 12)
  - Gesprochene Musik, no. 1, Holograph score 3 p.; 9 1/2 x 12 3/4 in. (Box 109, Folder 13)
  - Gesprochene Musik, no. 2, Holograph (ink and pencil) 3 p.; 9 1/4 x 12 3/4 in. (Box 109, Folder 13a)
  - Valse, Ozalid reproduction of holograph score with composer's corrections, 11 p.; 9 1/2 x 13 in. (Box 109, Folder 14)
  - Valse, Ozalid holograph transparencies 11 p.; 9 12 x 13 in. (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Fugue on the Name B-E-C-A-C-D, in un-becacd style, Holograph score [by Spencer?] 17 p.; 11 1/4 x 14 1/2 in. (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - From"Leaves of Grass" (Song of Myself, 32) by Walt Whitman, Ozalid holograph transparencies 4 l.; 10 1/2 x 14 in. (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Erlkoenig [Phantoms, op. 81, no. 3], Ozalid holograph transparencies 15 l.; 11 x 14 in. (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Song Without Words, Copyist's holograph score (pencil) 3 folded l; 9 1/2 x 12 in. (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Variations on Theme by John Scott Trotter, Holograph (pencil) 12 p.; 11 1/4 x 13 & 9 1/2 in. (Box 110, Folder 6)
    Incomplete except for fugue (finale).
  - Poem on a Theme by John Scott Trotter, Holograph score (pencil) 12 p.; 11 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Passacaglia on a Theme by John Scott Trotter, Holograph (pencil) 52 p.; 11 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - March on a Theme by John Scott Trotter, Holograph score (pencil) 26 p.; 11 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Quartet for Oboe, Clarinet, Bassoon, and Viola, Ozalid reproduction of copyist's score and parts 7p, 4 parts. (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Enamored Harequin, op. 94, Sketch, holograph condensed score 4 p.; 10 x 13 in (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - Passacaglia on a Theme by John Scott Trotter, Holograph (pencil) 16 p.; 10 1/2 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Variations on a Theme by John Scott Trotter, Incomplete holograph 40 p.; 10 3/4 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 110, Folder 13)
  - Variations on a Theme by John Scott Trotter., Holograph score (pencil) 50 p.; 10 3/4 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 110, Folder 14)
  - Sonata for violin and piano, op. 21, Photocopy of holograph score 34 p.; 10x 15 in. (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Poem, March, Passacaglia, and Variations on a Theme by John Scott Trotter, Photocopies of copyist's scores, 10 x 14 in. (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Poem, March, Passacaglia, and Variations on a Theme by John Scott Trotter, Photocopies of copyist's scores, 10 x 14 in. (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Klavierstuecke,Op. 78a and Op. 78b, Photocopy of holograph 6 l.; 10 x 15 in. (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Klapperstorch [Der Tierkries, op. 52, no. 3. Klapperstorch], Photocopy of holograph score 1 l.; 10 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Variations on Peter's Song, for cello and piano, Photocopy of holograph score (12 p.) and part (3 p.); 8 1/2 x 14 1/4 in. (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Zum Hochzeitstag von Fred Jackson mit Edeltraut (Peter) Lorinser., Photocopy of holograph, 3 p. (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Ladies in Retirement, Photocopy of copyist's condensed score 67 l.; 9 1/4 x 11 1/2 in. (Box 111, Folder 8)
  - Auf Wunsch von Friedrika Amlinger, for voice and piano., Photocopy of holograph, 3 p. (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - Gruss an Grete und Hans Fuchs, for clarinet and piano, Photocopy of holgraph, 3 p. (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Gates of Carven Jade, Photocopy of holograph score 9 l.; 10 x 15 in. (Box 111, Folder 11)
  - Vom sterbenden Rokoko, op. 16, no. 1, Photocopy of published score 5 l.; 10 x 15 in. (Box 111, Folder 12)
  - Vom sterbenden Rokoko, op. 16, no 2, Photocopy of published score 6 l.; 10 x 15 in. (Box 111, Folder 13)
  - Vom sterbenden Rokoko, op. 16, no. 3, Photocopy of published score 5 l.; 10 x 15 in. (Box 111, Folder 14)
  - Drei Praeludien, Op. 10, Photocopy of published score 15 l.; 12 x 15 in. (Box 111, Folder 15)
  - Stammbuchverse, fuer Klavier zu 2 haenden, Op. 13, Photocopy of published score, 15 l.; 10 x 15 in. (Box 111, Folder 16)
  - Melodische Skizzen, Op. 9, no. 1, Photocopy of published score 5 l.; 10 x 15 in. (Box 111, Folder 17)
  - Melodische Skizzen, Op. 9 no. 2, Photocopy of published score 3 l; 10 x 15 in. (Box 111, Folder 18)
  - Chansons sans paroles, Photocopy of holograph score 3 p.; 10 x 12 in. (Box 111, Folder 19)
  - String Quartet in A minor, op. 12, manuscript transparencies (Box 111, Folder 20)
  - Sonata for violin and piano, op. 21, Ozalid copyist's transparencies of score (41 p.) and part (16 p.); 9 1/2 x 13 in. (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Vanities of Vanities, All is Vanity, op. 79, Signed, Ozalid reproduction of holograph score 38 p.; 11 1/3 x 14 in. (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Sonata for violin and piano, op. 21, Ozalid reproduction of copyist's score (41 p.) and part (16 p.), 2 scores, 2 parts; 11 1/2 x 15 in. (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Third symphony, Op. 75, Third movement, Incomplete photocopy holograph, pp. 63-71,; 9 x 12 in. (Box 112, Folder 4)
    First version, different from published version.
  - Chansons sans paroles, Photocopy of copyist's score 3 folded l.; 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Kammersymphonie, Photocopy of holograph score 32 p.; 11 x 15 in. (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - The Last Tale, op. 88, Incomplete photocopy of holograph condensed score 31 l.; 10 x 15 in. (Box 112, Folder 7)
  - Cantata of the Bitter Herbs, op. 65, Photocopy of holograph score, left margin cut off 34 l.; 10 x 15 in. (Box 112, Folder 8)
  - Suite "The Idle Stroller", Holograph score 106 p.; 11 1/2 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - Circus Overture, Holograph score 34 p.; 12 1/4 x 17 in. (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - Remember, Photocopy of holograph 3 p; 8 1/2 x 11 in. (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Last Tale, Op. 88, Ozalid reproduction of holograph score, 173 p. (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Third Symphony, op. 75, Holograph score 99 p.; 13 1/3 x 11 in. (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - String Quartet, Op. 70, Holograph (ink), 59 p. 13 1/2 x 11 in. (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Spiel fuer Blasorchester, op. 39, Ozalid copyist's transparencies of score and parts, 1 score (28 l.) + 4 parts (122 l.) (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Cantata of the Bitter Herbs, Op. 65, Ozalid reproduction of holograph, 63p., 11 x 14 in. (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Address Unknown, Photocopy of holograph condensed score 172 p.; 9 x 11 1/2 in. (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Address Unknown, Photocopy of holograph score 172 p.; 9 x 11 1/2 in. (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Cat and the Canary, Ozalid reproduction of copyist's condensed score 47 p.; 9 x 12 in. (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - None Shall Escape, Copyist's condensed score 57 p.; 10 1/2 x 14 in. (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Address Unknown, Holograph piano-conductor score 69 p.; 9 1/2 x 13 in. (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Ladies in Retirement, Ozalid reproduction of copyist's condensed score 67 l.; 9 1/2 x 13 in. (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - 3 Originalstuecke fuer das elektrische Welte-Mignon Klavier, 2 Photocopies of holograph score 25 l.; 11 x 13 in. (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - Doodles (Cartoons), Cartoon sketches (pencil and ink) 7 sleeves. (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Skizzenblaetter (Sketches), 1950s-1960s; Holograph (pencil) 133 p.; 5 1/4 x 3 1/2; 9 1/2 x 7 1/2 in. (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - "In a Romantic Mood" (Ghost Breakers), Ozalid reproduction of copyist's condensed score 6 p.; 9 x 12 in. (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Selections from Outcast., Ozalid reproductions of copyist's condensed scores, 5 condensed scores; 9 1/2 x 12 1/4 in. (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Vocal accompaniments for possible Bing Crosby use, Holograph scores (pencil) 2 scores; 10 3/4 x 12 3/4 and 9 x 12 1/4 in. (Box 115, Folder 5)
    Includes "My Romance" and "I'll Take You Home Again Kathleen"
  - Miscellaneous teaching material (Box 115, Folder 5a)
    Gift of J.S. Trotter
  - Sketches, Holograph (pencil) 8 l.; 103/4 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 115, Folder 6)
    Includes arrangement of Mozart's Piano Sonata in F, K. 332, XV/4 and other unidentified sketches.
  - Fragment, Ozalid holograph transparency of 3 bars of music 1 l.; 11 x 14 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous typescript, 2 typescript pages (Box 115, Folder 8a)
  - Main Title (Address Unknown?), Holograph condensed score of main theme 2 p.; 9 1/2 x 12 in. (Box 115, Folder 8b)
  - "Remember?" from "Profiles", Holograph (ink), 2 l. folded, 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 115, Folder 8c)
  - "The Merry Billy-goat" from "Profiles", Holograph (ink), 2 l. folded, 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous music examples from other composers (Box 115, Folder 8e)
  - Kleine Overture fuer Blaeser und Schlagzeug, Holograph score 8 p.; 10 1/2 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - Komodie fuer Orchester, Holograph score 38 p.; 10 1/2 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 115, Folder 8g)
    unfinished first attempt
  - Untitled fragment, Holograph score (ink) 13 p.; 10 1/2 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 115, Folder 8h)
  - Fragment from Hyperion, op. 71, Holograph score pp. 55-65; 10 1/2 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 115, Folder 8i)
  - Miscellaneous Sketches, Holograph 127 p. (Box 115, Folder 9)
    Includes "Fifth Symphony," "Improvisation in Three Movements" (for Piatigorsky), "Sixth Symphony," and other unidentified sketches.
  - Variation Fantasy Sketch, Holograph score (pencil) 2 p.; 12 1/2 x 17 in. (Box 115, Folder 9)
    [Quartets, oboe, clarinet, bassoon, viola, op. 98]
  - Fuge aus der Geographie, Photocopy of holograph, 6 p. (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Cantata of the Bitter Herbs, ozalid reproduction, 26 p. (Box 116, Folder 1a)
    Vocal part
  - Cantata of the Bitter Herbs, Ozalid reproduction of copyist's score, 26 p. (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - Dedication, for Franzi and Irving on their wedding day, Photocopy of holograph, 3 p. (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Scheherazade [The Last Tale, op. 88], Percussion part, 20 p. (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - The Last Tale, op. 88, Photocopy of holograph title page and first page of music, 3 p. (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - The Last Tale, Photocopy of holograph score, 173 p. (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - None Shall Escape, Photocopy of holograph score 216 p.; 9 x 11 1/2 in. (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - None Shall Escape, Photocopy of holograph condensed score 57 p.; 9 x 11 1/2 in. (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - "The Ghost Breakers." Cast. 2nd Revision., Ozalid reproduction of copyist's condensed score 1 p.; 9 x 12 in. (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Abie's Irish Rose. Nostalgia., Holograph score 4 p.; 9 1/2 x 12 in. (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Abie's Irish Rose, Holograph condensed score (pencil) 40 p.; 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Abie's Irish Rose, Script/timing sheets 74/13 l.; 8 1/2 x 11 in. (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Adagio elegiaco, Holograph score (ink) 3 p.; 10 x 13 in. (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Klavier violin sonate, op. 44, Holograph score 28 p.; 10 3/4 x 13 1/4 in. (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Serenade fuer violine und bratsche, op. 25, Holograph score (ink) 17 p.; 13 x 9 1/2 in. (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - 3 Originalstuecke fuer das elektrische Welte-Mignon Klavier, Holograph score (ink) 25 p.; 10 3/4 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Sonatinetta, op. 78b, Holograph score 12 p.; 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - String Quartet Fragment, Ozalid holograph transparencies 4 p.; 11 x 14 in. (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Kammersymphonie fuer zehn Solo-instrumente, Holograph score (ink) 32 p.; 10 1/2 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - An mein Vaterland, op. 23, Holograph 176 p.; 10 3/4 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - An mein Vaterland, op. 23, Not a holograph, but with his corrections. 286 p.; 10 1/2 x 13 3/4 in. (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - No. 1 Besetzung., Holograph score 14 p.; 10 1/2 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 119, Folder 3)
    An early version (?) of 1st movement of Bunte Suite, op. 48.
  - Bunte Suite, op. 48, no. 4. "Marionetten-Tanz", Holograph score (ink and pencil) 17 p.; 10 3/4 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Bunte Suite, op. 48, no. 4. Marionetten-Tanz, Holograph condensed score (pencil) 8 p.; 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Bunte Suite, op. 48. "Coney Island", Holograph 18 p.; 11 x 13 1/2 in. (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - Bunte Suite, op. 48. "Coney Island" (parts), Copyist's holograph, 13 parts; 9 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Streichquartett, no. 11, op. 34, Incomplete photocopy of holograph pp. 14, 27, 29, 41, 4 p.; 10 x 15 in. (Box 119, Folder 8)
  - Der KinderNeujahrstraum, op. 19, Holograph score 60 p.; 10 3/4 x 13 in. (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Im fernen Osten, Holograph score 12 p.; 10 1/2 x 13 in. (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Medea, Holograph score 23 p.; 10 1/2 x 12 in. (Box 120, Folder 3)